[Music]
Hello friends, I, Sumit Bhandari, welcome you on behalf of Health in.com.
Thank you very much for watching this video.
Today our topic is your complaint and
an
explanation from my side. See, most of the time we get
messages, emails and comments etc. that
you mean maximum people who are
searching on the internet, their
requirement is that they want comparison of two or four
popular products in India or
any new product.
So everyone complains to us
that why don't we upload these comparison videos.
Look, I will talk very frankly here, it has been
roughly five to six years since I
watched videos of any person on health insurance on the internet. When
I started, there were no videos at that time.
After that, nowadays, by
chance, I skip because I don't watch much of anything
on the internet, except chess. So, if
by chance I clip someone, then
within a minute, I close that video.
Reason  What happens, try
to understand this thing fundamentally calmly,
suppose today a product has been
launched in the market, ICC Lord
Elevate, some time before this, it was a very
popular product, Niva Bappa's Rio 2.0,
then there is a product by Care Supreme, these are
three such products which have been very popular for a long time,
okay, so when any person
goes to search on the internet, do
n't feel bad, I will say something clear,
when you are going to buy a policy,
your mind is brainwashed
that these three-four products, these three-
four products are very good,
in insurance today around 35-40 companies each
have three-four products, there are 200
health insurance products, okay,
without taking any name, I will tell you about one product,
that product was launched in the rural market in 2019,
then it came in the urban market in 2011,
people from urban channels sold them,
even today that policy, that is, the 15-17 year old
policy, is still in India  That it is one of the best
policy, how is the best policy,
what is the definition of best policy, that the
policy which if God forbid your claim
comes today, then it pays almost the entire claim,
so the product which was
launched in 2009 is still sufficient and excellent for a health insurance
claim,
meaning almost all the money is
received in that policy, there is no limit of any kind,
so what happens when
we have read such a product, then naturally
many times the old products are also a bit cheaper, I am just
talking about an example,
now whenever suppose you
bring a new model today, add two-three
superficial features in it, what are superficial features,
such features which
are a little advanced but they have
nothing to do with the engine performance dynamics,
all the chassis inside is the same, only
its outlook, like Honda image will not
come, so mainly the outlook is changed in it,
one or two relevant features are added
but its rate increases by 50, 60, 70 thousand
Why is this done because if the customer
company also makes new dies, then it will be a
little more expensive for them. It
seems that how much iron is there, that means
their costing increases by four times,
but they earn 10 times more than that
and those who are selling the policies, they get
a new advantage for the dealers
because in India there are many people
who are from the business community who
change their vehicles within three to four years, a
facelift is brought for them,
so whenever a new
product comes in the insurance, it is basically a facelift.
What innovation has happened in the industry today after 2010, the concept of restoring
came, recharge came, refill, all are of the same kind
of concept, the nominal bonus used to be at
40, 50, today it is 5, 600, 700, the
latest product came two years ago in
which your policy is increased 11 times, that
is, if you take a policy of 25 lakhs, then
even 2.25 lakhs will be treated as 2.25 crores after a few
years, so these bonus type features
New people have come but
what does one need above the basic level, why is he taking that consumer policy
or its basic and simple
work is only that if tomorrow there is a claim,
my hospital bill will be settled, then this does
not give scope to health insurance,
why don't I put a comparison, I have
three products, Care Supreme, SDFC Ergo
Optim Secure, Niva Bupa, let's
assume Elevate as well, let's see these
four products, I will compare them and see what
you will get, if
you want to compare then put their
brochures side by side and do it, when a
person gives his comparison, in most of the
cases I don't watch much videos,
so I don't know, but
I feel that in that the person is
giving his version,
if he discusses each point of everything, then the
interpretation he is giving or the
feature that he tells, he has one or the other
motive behind it, okay, very rarely you will find
that there is a comparison of two products, so
what is the meaning of comparison, keep the brochures of two
companies side by side  Look at them, you
can do this work yourself too, what comparison do you
want, that too you should ultimately
look at as a consumer, the thought in the back of your
mind is that
I should search on the internet and get help
and buy the policy, okay, the
comparisons that always come for new products,
most of the new products are not good for the consumer,
I am repeating, the time when
Apollo Main Easy Health
Policy was made, that product was
launched in 2008, in 7 or 8, when that
product was launched in 8 or 9, even today if
someone had that policy then that policy would be closed, the Apollo
Main Easy Health Policy was there even today,
if that policy of any company was
running in 2024, I am repeating, the 16-17
year old product which was made, even today
if any person had that policy, it was
sufficient, there was no deficiency in that policy,
what is
required for the hospital bill of a consumer is  Now
after that the company made a product Optima
Secure, Optima sorry Optima Restore, it was a
better product, it was a bit costly
but had reasonable pricing, had good features and was
value for money, but when SDFC
ARG made Optima Secure, it was
totally made in favor of the company, the
consumer is
not getting much benefit from it, now someone will
comment to me that are you
against that product, no,
people have also taken that policy from us, but what I
say is that I do
not happily recommend that product to anyone, okay, I have
sworn to someone, take it, there is
no flaw in the product, but it is
not suitable, most of the people are not able to run that policy,
now a new product has come from
ICICI Lombard's Elevate, if I
compare it with the old
comprehensive product of ICICI Lombard,
sometime back, that is, I am
talking about from 2006, at that time,
their product was the same, even today the
product is the same in 2004-24  It is almost the same,
five or six new things have been added to it,
those five or six things which the consumer does not
need, the seller is
getting more benefit from them, see this is one
such thing that I can also suppose as a
doctor I know that if
someone gets cured with a medicine worth ₹ then
why should I give him a medicine worth 00, you know but
I will give this medicine worth 00 only when the
MR or the company gives me some
extra money after selling the medicine worth 00, so there is
only one purpose of not putting comparison,
most of the new products are
not value for money, okay if
you want to compare anything then
pick up its brochure, you will have to read it,
write brochures of two companies, read them, how much
time does it take, one hour, in one hour you do the
comparison yourself, in one hour you will
find 10 videos and watch them slowly, you are only
confusing yourself,
okay now the second thing which is a very big
point of people is that  We also get
complaints that
you do not answer the comments directly.
Look,
I will tell you about the comment of a person that came through the letter.
Okay, today's video will be a little long
because the complaints are also of this type,
so I will have to give
you some time to handle them. Now this morning itself,
someone posted
a comment around 4:00 am. I will
not take names. Very helpful sir,
thank you. I have only one question. The base
policy date is different. The super topper policy
date is different.
What happens in this situation? If the
base policy expires and the second one is nullified,
what will happen? Now see what happened. Now let me
answer this thing in front of you. If this person is
looking at the policy, look, fundamentally you should never do this.
If your policy is of the same
date, then only that is the best option, this is the
best practice. If it is not there, then do
not think too much about it because
you have already taken the policy, there is
no need to bother yourself about it. Whatever happens is the
pre-decided process of the company.
The company never makes it public,
and it's always in the company's favor. If
your claim comes up, if the company's
intentions are not good, they will twist it around for
their own benefit. So,
what's the actual answer to this? Because I can't type for so long. I'm
speaking very quickly. The actual thing is,
whether you buy the policy again or somehow have the same
date as your renewal
date, that's the best option. If its date is the same,
if you're feeling very upset, stressed, or stressed about this,
then you can get that date changed.
One way is to get a new policy.
Otherwise, it will continue like this, so there's no need to
worry. Super top claims
come very rarely, you can handle it. Now,
I don't have time to answer so many things in a comment
because
what happens is I have to write the answer correctly.
I
can write a couple of lines at the most. I have to
give a proper answer to something honestly.  Time will definitely take time for that,
right? So,
now the third big complaint is that
you take money from people, right? You consider yourself a great expert for health
insurance consultation, you
create a perception in the market, you
confuse people and you do not give roundabout answers to the real thing, you do
not give clear answers, you keep talking in a roundabout way,
look, I will tell you fundamentally this thing very
honestly, my age is 49
and a half, two adults, one child. If
I have to take a policy today, I live in Vrindavan,
my office is in Vadodara, right now I may have
some borderline health conditions in
my body, so suppose today
I have to take my policy, then from the time I was
born till now, we will
first spend a day or two compiling all our health history of my wife and child,
then accordingly we will see
in which city we have to stay for the long term,
then how much cover do we need,
after doing all this analysis  Four hours
pass easily, okay, and if I
also have to buy a policy today, if I do it
calmly, then I will spend two-three days
in selecting a policy for myself,
why am I saying this, right now
we had a
question from some person that he made a
mistake while buying the policy, yesterday I have a
friend of his, his client, he
sold the policy to someone, we
worked part-time and sold the policy, then
his cancer claim came, so that
claim is going on for the last three days, so fundamentally in that, he made
five-six mistakes, he
chose the wrong hospital, the hospital staff
discharges him at 4 o'clock and the claim that was applied for, he
gave half the documents for applying the claim, so the cashless approval did not
come and there will be an investigation, he was
admitted on the 20th,
his claim approval came today, okay, no, he was
admitted on the 19th, so the
claim approval came on the third day, so that
in the hospital, the claim that came for him was done by the
madam whose husband's  A claim had come from
his wife, someone said that cancer is
not covered at all, then he asked me
that yes madam is saying that cancer is
not covered, then is cancer covered in the policy that I sold to him,
then I told him no, now what is the matter that that
brother has gone out to sell the
policy, he has sold 1015 policies, agents,
advisors, consultants, they themselves do not
know when cancer is covered in health insurance or not, so the
consumer, the
patient, sitting in the hospital, although
I told them that you will get your claim and that
claim was also approved, okay, the point is
not that we have more knowledge, the point is that the
policy that they sold to 101 people,
they themselves have the knowledge and have come after selling wrong things,
okay, so when such a thing comes in front of me, then
I remember that best practice that
we started the policy consultation, from
which region did we start it, in
India today when a person goes to buy a policy, then where does
his interest first come from, that is,
where does the interest come from
Some person comes and advises him, if someone
in his vicinity has made a
claim or something, then he tries to say
that hey friend, someone has suffered a loss, so that I do
n't face the same tomorrow, then with selfish motive, the
person gets interested and starts looking
whether I should buy a policy and if I have to
buy one, then which policy,
what will I do to buy it, first of all he will ask some of his
friends, okay married people, there is
some link in the office, brother, have
you bought a policy, tell me which one,
how is your experience, then after spending a
day or two, they search, then when they get
time inside the office or after coming home, they go on the
internet and start searching,
so
google's time or best health insurance
policy in India or best health
insurance p p in
2024, in this way they will post the message, now
when they enter this keyword,
some insurance companies with SCO already
appear for it, then they do not understand
which one to do, then there they see some
online portal etc.  They go there and start
comparing.
Then by chance they come to know that what happens is that they are
going to do it. Within a few days they
start gaining some confidence. I have come to
know that till now
they must have spent at least 15-20 hours doing all this research. While
walking ask someone because you are
wasting your time or
investing time, you are investing it on that. So, by
estimation, if a person is not much, even if he
earns Rs. 400 per hour, if his
income is Rs.
500, if not Rs. 200 per hour, then that is already
spent, which is called management. We
have only one time, that is the time which we are
spending in research. So what did you do in this time?
Within five to seven days,
you collected a lot of data,
information etc. Now you are analyzing that data. So
what happens gradually, in this time
frustration starts increasing.  So
what happens when we get tired is that we
take advice from someone and if someone's
video is so good then after watching it we
give some comparison or try some
financial influencer and
search on Google what is a financial influencer,
okay how financial influencers are
paid by the company, so what are those financial
influencers, they are experts,
their way of speaking, their presentation is
not like ours, that we just sit and make such videos,
they must have a proper studio,
they have explained everything well
and because the company has paid them professionally, they
talk in favor of the company
or that policy agent, who is an
agent of the insurance company, will
promote his policy and
tell the positive things and will keep the negative things aside,
now in every policy out of 10
things, eight are good and two are bad,
in every policy, two things are bad, that is
not told to any consumer, so when this person is doing this,
he has spent 20-25 hours, he is
not keeping the accounts but he watched for two hours at night and let's
go  While wandering around, he went on
YouTube, went to Reddit, and while doing this, he started getting to know about the
world, when he got confused,
one day he got tired and said, "Come on friend, whatever
someone I know has taken will
also be good, this person is saying it is very good, you
end the hassle by taking a policy, so what
happens is that if
someone is not married within 35 years, then he
says, or whoever I marry, the girl will be
good, I will marry whoever I get, so
most of the people do this, as per my experience,
most of the people do this and many
people do this, they
go to the bank for that policy or they have taken a loan or a
credit card, or while sitting, they get a
call from some person saying that we are
calling from such and such company, so this
is an offer for you, in this way they think, come on friend, let's
take this policy, now
clinically there are four things here, number one,
before you are selecting the policy,
you had not made your goal that what are
my needs in my future life as long as I live,
because they  They do not have the knowledge, they have the
information, they have the data but they do
not have the knowledge, if they do not have the knowledge then they assume, they take a
policy of 10 lakhs, 25
lakhs, whatever they understand by chance,
one thing many people do not finalize it at all, they take
5-10 lakhs, friend finish your work, I have been
wasting time for so many days, take it,
many times it happens that by the 30th the
data has to be submitted in the company, then
someone has come to the home office, so
for filing the return they
take some policy or the other, whatever the friend has taken, they
put the responsibility of that on him, you must have taken a
good one, so they take the policy accordingly,
now what happened is that we did
not set our objective, did not do our goal setting,
what is the second thing to take a policy, the second
problem is that when you are
buying a product,
what things do you have to keep in mind at the time of buying the product,
what are the best practices to buy a
policy, you do not know that, so
most of the people do not follow it, I have my own
data, my own analysis that
Nine out of 10 people who have
bought insurance policies online have
mistakes in their policies. A lot of
people come to us, almost all of them,
I am saying here that nine out of 10, almost
all of them have made mistakes in their policies.
Why do they not know when they are
buying the policy? The person in front is not telling them this.
I am saying this again. This
video will get long. Okay, so for this reason,
because we have to talk in detail, at that
time we do not know what are the
best practices of the policy we are buying. When you
go to the person in front of you, you will keep
buying policies. Let me take a relevant example of this.
Like if you are
going to buy an automobile, then at the time of buying a car, there is
a concept called
PDI. You know, after inspection, there is a
pre-delivery inspection. There is a
checklist for inspecting it. To the one
who does not have that checklist, the dealer will
give any car and leave. In such insurance,
you have bought a policy online, that
means how many cases do we have? How many
cases do we have? That means such cases are in thousands.
I have people who are honest,
good, very nice people but they have made a mistake by hiding it in their
policy.
Okay, so I don't know in what manner the policy is bought.
Thirdly, when you are
entering into a policy as a contract,
you should know
what things are
not covered in the policy that I am getting and in which circumstances will I
get the claim and in which case will I not get it.
Like you should
know about any YouTuber. Number two, we should know
that if I am getting unlimited sum assured
or I am getting five times bonus, then
what will be the effect on my premium after that
because when the company is telling you that the
policy of Rs 10 lakh will be
treated to Rs 50 lakh in the coming time. It sounds very good to hear,
greed also comes in the mind. So, when we
took this top policy in which we gave money of Rs 10 lakh and the
company promised to give a claim of Rs 50 lakh, then the
company will give a claim of Rs 50 lakh. If you give a claim of Rs 50 lakh, then it will not give
from its own pocket,
who gives from its own pocket, no one
gives, so you had paid the money.  If you are
running a policy for Rs. 10 lakhs, tomorrow it will increase, so
these things happen that at
which stage your premium will increase, how much
premium will increase and how much
premium will be charged on different terms in the coming time, you are
not able to check all this because this is not your job and there are
many such things, so two-three
things came to my mind and I said them, many people make
mistakes, okay, fourthly finally no
person has 100% idea of ​​this thing that what will happen to
me  Has the product been delivered, is it
correct and how to check it, that is,
how to inspect it after delivery, okay, so when these
four are such big points that maximum
people are not aware of it, no one talks about it,
okay, then our
positioning is that I am
not recommending you any cheap policy here, as per your
need, as per your capacity, as per
your 10, 15, 20, 25 parameters, as per
our discussion with you, we
feel that these three or four policies are good for you,
take them brother, I have taken these four policies,
take any one of these, it is very good for you,
I am not selling anything to you, so
when we are doing so much data research,
after that we have
data of our clients in real time, we collect research from the market,
take feedback from the hospital,
after that we know
which companies are actually running in the trend nowadays at the ground level, okay, these
claim treatment ratios, these claim ratios, these are useless
nonsense, no policy has anything to do with these,
you are buying any company
Where will you check the business model? You
know, in insurance, in some companies, the
commission on the product is 5
or 10, and in some, it is even 30 or 40.
Suppose you bought a policy of Rs. 1000, in that the
commission was 10, so since you had
000, if the commission in that was above 30, then
your commission is 10, since you went to Hajj, where will you
check it? The policy that you sold, is it
okay? I am not saying this, I am
not talking against the agent community here,
but the truth is right, isn't it? What are we
charging for? What are we
consulting on? We are
telling you impartially about the policy that you want to take, wherever you
want, we can take or not give, do we have no
role in that? If
someone tells you to take it from us, then we have a
checklist on which the client should be compliant.
We do not even make policies for every person,
right? Our stomach is full,
we do not need any policy,
that too, we have it here, okay if
People can take consultation if they want, those who don't want to take it, don't take it
brother,
keep doing it on your own, it means we don't have any
responsibility towards the country that we should do all this, the
whole world will do it, but what happens here is that
we have clearly mentioned in our process,
we will tell you from where you can take the policy, so for that
if I
charged a fee of 699 from a person, or I charged a fee of 000,
honestly put your hand on your heart and tell me
how many hours you have spent in researching health insurance for two to four months to two to four years, then
you will know the value of your work,
brother, you must know that
I earn so much that my capacity is,
someone must be earning at least 000 in an
hour, okay, even if you spent 20 hours, then you have
spent it from your own pocket, okay, you had to give time to your family, that is what is involved in it,
so I am
talking rationally, I am not saying that you should take
consultation from us, I am saying that
because of this we are not putting pressure on you  The time that is being invested is
my team, my team has expenses, our
overheads, from where will we cover it, when we will give it, so how do you
expect, okay, you
don't give consultation, I am perfectly okay with it, it's
okay, ours is
not a long term plan that we have to give our whole life, we will
give it for a few years, then after that we will do our bhajan
kirtan, we will get busy with that,
okay, so for this reason practically we
charge fees, look, I will say
a very brotherly thing here, for those people
who are still sitting in this video by watching,
I am
not saying here that I am a big fan, I have the
knowledge of the world, only I have the
knowledge, you do not have it, no one has such a
thing, I do not
keep anyone under any misconception about anything, I do not have any pride, for
my reputation, for
my false o, I do
not live under such misconception, mostly I am a bad
type of person, most of the world is intelligent,
most of the people we meet are
more intelligent than us, but
what is the matter, we are working in the same field, so
We have their up to date pulse,
we have what is there in the market and
I am not wrong in telling someone to do that, do that, I
love give them a choice of joining these two or
three companies, what problem
arises, see the
problem that most people are facing in insurance is that
they think that they will be
able to do it, do not be under any illusion,
if you want to buy a policy in this health insurance industry on your own, then at
least you will have to
spend 30-40 hours practically, honestly, do
research for a month or two,
study well, do not give us money, do not give money to anyone,
you do it with your own understanding, but that proper information, that which
you have, right, that information, properly
synthesize it, analyze it,
if you extract knowledge from it like sugarcane juice, it will take
time to reach it, right,
you can do it on your own also, but it is not like that you
watch a couple of videos and
read a couple of documents  You will not come to us to buy such a policy, most of the
people who come to us are confused, they have the
knowledge of the world, despite us telling them,
many people do not understand at all, okay, then you have to
understand this thing, okay,
if you want to buy a policy on your own, then
spend quality time on it, understand this thing, the
new product that comes in the market, the
company has launched it for its own benefit,
not for your benefit, in this misunderstanding, I don't want to use this
word, but it is
foolish
if you expect that the
new product that you have picked up has been made for you,
no, it has been made so that the
dealer, the agent who is selling the policy in between can
easily
sell it to you by twisting it around, what did I say,
even the products of 2009 are in the market today, there are
products of 2011 as well, the
products of 2009-13 are also sitting in the market which
beat today's products as well, today's products of 2009,
20, 21, 22, 23, 24 in the last four years  In five years, the
so-called big products
easily beat them.
Beat in what sense, by pressing fully you get the open dola
claim, there is no need to worry at all.
Inherently, what happened was that you
opened an account in a bank. You
opened an account in a bank. There was a zero balance in one
account, there was an account with a balance of 5000, there was
an
account with a balance of 500, there was an account with a balance of 2 lakhs.
Everyone will get this facility, but
if you withdraw 000 from your account through ATM, then
money comes out from ATMs in four accounts, brother. So, there is no such
research. There is no such
thing that there is a misunderstanding, like a
small point remained. Many people have
this misunderstanding
that some insurance company is very
good and some is distributing a lot of money, the
claim settlement ratio is high, this is
high. This data is
not available in real time and
a selective portion is presented to you from within it.
Okay, this is a big controversial issue,
one day I exposed the truth.  So this claim
settlement scheme will be exposed and
all the company people will come after me. Okay,
what things are hidden in this thing that they say, claim settled at 99, I don't want to tell you because I don't believe in
it. So
one thing you have to remove from your mind is,
don't live under the misconception that this company
is very great, its brand is big, it does
n't have a lot of money, insurance is a business of claim
rejection. Okay, don't
live under the misconception that any company will pay more money.
Okay, so basically I
wanted to share my heart's feelings. Okay,
almost all of my
videos, I start with
no script, I say whatever is in my heart, I will
cut it and post it like that without editing,
just cut
two seconds from the beginning,
cut two seconds from the end, I will post such a video.
Okay, so my request to all of you will be
that whenever you buy a policy, at
least I will give you a small hint.
If you have done your research till now or
you  You have bought your policy from anywhere,
do you have the proposal form of your policy
or have you read
something called proposal form while doing research, okay,
if you haven't read it then you haven't done
anything in insurance yet, you are on a very very weak
wicket, ever hit, this is
called hit wicket, there is no need to bowl to the opponent, the
open player has hit on his own leg, the
insurance is full of
best practices, best practices, if
you want to know then you will have to pay a fee, it is a
very simple thing, okay, there is a small
claim, this cancer claim, which was
cleared this morning only, if that
claim is not received then the client has lost
six lakh
rupees from his pocket, okay, and those who sold the policy do
not know this, okay,
they had to taunt them all their life because they
seem to be distant relatives, the
world is sending policies to relatives, okay, so
people are not doing their work professionally, I have no problem
in saying this, the
online policies that people are buying at 99,
I think that
I will not even say that such a thing is
okay, because the same thing  It is that
we have to take responsibility for the entire country as per our religion, as per the
knowledge we have received,
whatever we have learnt from our gurus, we
share that with you, daily
experience, our client is our guru,
we do not need to go anywhere, our claim is
our guru, the hospital is our guru, there is
a doctor, he is the one who is teaching us everything, so do
not stretch it for too long, you
people will get bored, it will be repetitive, there are
a lot of things to say, okay, by chance if you like
any of my things then you can
appreciate it,
you can leave some comment about it,
okay, it will help someone,
if you feel that somewhere I am sounding very
pompous or with ego,
then you can give your feedback, okay,
if I have an attitude problem,
I will
definitely try to change it, okay, but I do not live in false pride, I do
not have such pride in
life, okay, so if someone likes it, you
want us to keep working like this, there is no person like this
in between  We received
obscene messages etc., one or two people even threatened us etc. There are
some such people, they are young
people, so then our mood gets sour,
friend, is there no need for videos etc. If we
get love from a lot of people, then we will keep uploading videos from our side,
okay, and keep doing the work, it is a
simple job, okay, we have to work from 9 in the morning to 6 in the afternoon,
so if
any of you liked the video, then
like it, if you feel that we are doing
some good work, then definitely I can
make a request to you, I can
request you on my own right, that share this video as much as possible, whoever
feels like it can
also like this video, okay,
you took out time to watch this video and
listened to my explanation, so thank you very much
Jai Jai Shri Radhe